# **Yueun Kim**

★ yueunkim.dev in yueunk yueunk Denver, CO yk@yueunkim.dev

## **Summary**

I am a full-stack software engineer with a passion for collaborating to solve challenging problems. I have experience with the JavaScript, Ruby, and Go ecosystems. Most recently, I created Cascade , an open-source containerized application deployment solution with automated observability built with Node.js/Express, OpenTelemetry, React, and Terraform CDK for TypeScript.

## **Experience**

#### 2022 – present

#### **Creator, Software Engineer**

*Cascade* (https://try-cascade.github.io ☑)

- Prototyped and built Cascade, an open-source containerized application deployment solution with support for observability
- Streamlined the build and teardown processes of AWS infrastructure creation using Terraform CDK for TypeScript
- Published an NPM package for tracing instrumentation compatible with AWS Distro for OpenTelemetry Collector and AWS X-Ray
- Constructed an API server for communication with the AWS SDK
- Designed a GUI for visualization of resource creation statuses real-time via SSE
- Automated installation of Cascade using Docker (images, docker-compose)
- Authored a comprehensive technical case study on design decisions and challenges of building Cascade
- Collaborated with a remote team of 4 engineers across 3 timezones using agile workflow

#### 2020 - 2022

#### **Software Engineer**

Open-source web applications and Launch School experience

- Developed open-source software using Ruby, Node.js, Express, React, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, HTML/CSS, and more
- Selected projects:
  - Yarn Basket: a real-time webhook debugging tool with custom endpoints (Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, DigitalOcean Droplet, Nginx, PM2)
  - The Shoppe: a database-backed e-commerce app (Node, React, MongoDB, Docker)
  - Flight Tracker: an SVG map for filtering and viewing airline routes (React, Docker)

#### 2014 - 2020

#### **Director of Piano Performance**

Vivaldi Music Academy

Crafted curricula for the piano department, trained piano instructors, and conducted
masterclasses and private lessons contributing to the highest growth rate in academy
history expanding from one to four locations in the Greater Houston area

#### Skills

## Backend

Node.js, Express, Ruby, Go, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful APIs

## Frontend

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Jest, HTML/CSS, Tailwind CSS

## Tooling

Git/GitHub, Docker, Linux, Bash, OpenTelemetry, AWS (S3, SQS, EC2, ECS), Terraform

#### **Education**

**Rice University,** Master of Music, Piano Chamber Music

**Northwestern University,** Master of Music, Piano Performance and Pedagogy

**Eastman School of Music,** Bachelor of Music, Piano Performance